https://www.delwp.vic.gov.au/privacy

Open submenu
Technology reveals more than 6,600 years of ancient wisdom at Budj Bim
Integrity complaints
Integrity framework (code of conduct)
Privacy
Information about privacy - what information we collect and why
On this page:How we collect personal information from this websiteWhat personal information do we collect?Requests to provide information Automatic collection through the website Automatic collection by third-party software vendorsUse and disclosureSocial mediaLinks to non-vic.gov.au websites Security of your personal information Access and correctionCustomer Contact CentreContact usThe Victorian Government values and is committed to protecting your privacy.We handle your personal information in accordance with the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic) (PDP Act), Public Records Act 1973 (Vic), Health Records Act 2001 (Vic) and other applicable legislation.This Privacy Statement applies to information collected through the vic.gov.au website (www.vic.gov.au). For information about our broader collection, use, and disclosure of personal information, please contact:Foi.unit@delwp.vic.gov.auDepartment, Water, Land and PlanningPO Box 500East Melbourne 3002Contact us on 9637 8697.We may update this privacy statement from time to time. Any changes to this privacy statement will be published on this website.How we collect information from this website?There are 3 main ways that we may collect personal information from you:Requests to provide informationIn most circumstances, you will know if we are collecting personal information from you because you will be requested to provide it. For instance, if you submit a form to contact us through the website, we will ask you to provide your name and email address.Automatic collection through the websiteSome personal information is automatically collected as a result of your visit to our website. This information is collected using software techniques such as web server log file analysis, cookies and web beacons.Automatic collection by third party software vendorsWe use some third party software that collects information about your interaction with our website.When you visit our website, your web browser automatically sends certain information to these software providers.This statement covers each of these instances of personal information collection in more detail below.What personal information do we collect?The department collects a range of information from individuals who use this website.We may collect personal information that you choose to give us, or which may be required to access a particular service. This includes information collected via online forms, events and training registration, or when subscribing to receive newsletters. If you are requested to provide information a privacy “Collection Statement” displayed with the request will tell you what information is being collected, why the information is being collected, who generally and particularly *individuals and organisations the information will be disclosed to, any law that requires us to collect the information, the consequences of not providing the information (if any) and how to go about seeing the information you have provided about yourself and changing it if it is incorrect.Automatic collection through the websiteUse of cookies. We use first-party cookies and JavaScript code to collect information about visitors to this website. We use these to track how our visitors interact with this website, including where they came from, what they did on the site and whether they completed any transactions on the site. If you don't want to have cookies placed on your computer, you can disable them using your web browser. You will need to customise each web browser you use to turn off cookie tracking.If you opt out of using cookies, you will still have access to all the information and resources provided by this website, though some features may not work as expected.Automatic collection by third party software vendorsThis website uses several online tools to measure website use, which are provided by third party software vendors. We use these tools to help us make our site better. Much of the information collected this way relates to the computer that is used to interact with our website rather than the person using it.We use software by third parties, including:Google AnalyticsGoogle Tag ManagerHotJarFunnelbackMarketoLivepersonQualtricsFor further information on how these third-party software vendors handle your personal information, please review their privacy policies. Personal information may be provided to third parties when accessing this website. Information that may be shared to third parties includes:network location and IP addressthe date and time of your visit to our websitethe types of web browser (e.g. Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Safari) and operating system (e.g. Windows 10, Mac OS X etc.) you are usingFlash version, JavaScript support, screen resolution and screen colour processing abilityReferring site details (such as the URL that you came through to arrive at our website)Page visited and the time spent on each pageDocuments downloaded and search terms usedThe forms accessed on our websitePersonal identifiable informationUnique device identifierCookies and data about which page you visitedDevice information, hardware model, operating system information, app version, app usage, debugging information, browser informationGeo-location information (if enabled by user)May assign a unique user identifierAll of the third-party software vendors we use on this website comply with the PDP Act and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) legislation within the European Union.Third-party software vendors may alter how they collect and handle personal information at any time.Use and disclosureUse of web analytics dataWe use web analytics data for statistical purposes, such as to analyse, measure, and report on data about our website traffic and visits. This information helps us understand general user trends at an aggregate level, and improve our website, content, and user experience. The statistical information gathered does not identify you specifically.We may also use this information for security audits to protect against threats from hackers or other security purposes.We do not use this information to identify you or match it with any other personal information that we may collect from you, unless required to do so as part of an internal investigation or for a law enforcement-related purpose, in accordance with the PDP Act.Your site visit data is collected under the authority of Information Privacy Principle 1.1 of the PDP Act for the purposes stated above.Disclosure of web analytics dataApart from the third-party tools described in this Privacy Statement, we do not disclose your site visit data to any other third parties without your consent, unless we are required or authorised to do so by law. In the event of an investigation into suspected unlawful or improper activity, a law enforcement or government agency may use its legal authority to inspect our web server’s records (e.g. in relation to hacking or abusive messages).Can I opt-out of the collection of web analytics data?You cannot opt-out of the automatic collection of information that is used for analytical purposes, however, you may choose to disable cookies or delete any individual cookie. If you choose to disable cookies, the website may not function fully and your ability to browse, read, and download information contained on our website may be impaired. However, you may still access our services by contacting our office via other methods such as telephone, email, or mail.You can enable a “Do Not Track” setting on your browser to help protect your privacy. When Do Not Track is turned on, your browser will send a Do Not Track request to the sites you visit, and to the third parties whose content is hosted on those sites. However, many websites will still collect and use your browsing data regardless of the Do Not Track Request. This depends on individual sites’ privacy practices. Sending a Do Not Track request does not guarantee privacy protection.Instructions on how to enable the Do Not Track setting:Google ChromeInternet Explorer 11Mozilla FirefoxSafariSocial mediaWe use Twitter to communicate with the public about our work. We may collect any personal information that you provide us via the @DELWP_Vic Twitter under section 8C of the PDP Act, for the purposes of engaging and consulting with the public. Any personal information we collect via Twitter will be handled appropriately and in line with this privacy statement.Twitter may also collect your personal information for its own purposes. When you agree to Twitter’s terms of service and privacy policy, you agree to your information being transferred outside Victoria. To protect your privacy and the privacy of others, please do not post any personal information (including phone numbers and email addresses) in your comment, tweet, or reply. Additionally, please do not share personal information about others via social media.We use Sprout Social to manage the @DELWP_Vic Twitter account. Information collected by Twitter is also shared with Sprout Social.We have social media sharing links on this website. These are located on the left-hand side of a web page beside the text 'Share this page'. By clicking these links you are given the option to share the web page as a post on your social media account (Twitter, Facebook or LinkedIn). These social media networks may collect your personal information for their own purposes.Links to non-vic.gov.au websitesThis privacy statement does not apply to any external websites that are linked on the vic.gov.au website.We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of external websites. When you visit other websites, we recommend you read the privacy statements or policies of these websites before providing personal information.Security of your personal informationUnder the PDP Act, we have a responsibility to protect your personal information. We take reasonable steps to make sure that your personal information is protected from misuse, loss, and unauthorised access, modification, or disclosure. Access to systems, applications, and the information that we collect is limited to authorised staff members only.Further, any personal information that we collect and use for identifying user trends (for example, IP address) is aggregated and anonymised when generating reports.Access and correctionYou may request access to, or correction of, documents that contain your personal information which is in our possession. For information on how to make a request for access or correction, please contact us via the details below.In some cases, requests for access or correction will be handled in accordance with the Freedom of Information Act 1982 (Vic).Customer Contact CentreThe DELWP Customer Contact Centre provides information on behalf of DELWP and a number of other Government agencies. Information collected in the course of providing information on behalf of these agencies is done so in accordance with that agencies privacy statement. For more information, see the below links.VicEmergency HotlineCountry Fire Authority (CFA) privacy statementState Emergency Services (SES) privacy statementDepartment of Health and Human Services (DHHS) privacy statementMetropolitan Fire and Emergency Services Board (MFB) privacy statementEmergency Management Victoria (EMV) privacy statementDepartment of Jobs, Precincts and Regions (DJPR) privacy statementCustomer Contact Centre: Victorian Fisheries AuthorityVictorian Fisheries Authority (VFA) privacy statementCustomer Contact Centre: Game Management AuthorityGame Management Authority (GMA) privacy statementCustomer Contact Centre: Portable Long Service Leave AuthorityPortable Long Service Leave Authority (PLSLA) privacy statementCustomer Contact Centre: Solar HomesSolar Homes privacy statementCustomer Contact Centre: Energy Safe VictoriaEnergy Safe Victoria privacy statementCustomer Contact Centre: Agriculture Victoria and Department of Jobs, Precincts and RegionsAgriculture Victoria privacy statementDepartment of Jobs, Precincts and Regions (DJPR) privacy statement
Page last updated: 23/04/20
Close
